<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hipchat | rooted - a code blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://rootdown.net/blog/categories/hipchat/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rootdown.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-31T11:10:59-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://rootdown.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cameron Johnston]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HipChat LWRP for Chef]]></title>
    <link href="http://rootdown.net/blog/2012/05/04/hipchat-lwrp-for-chef/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-04T12:22:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://rootdown.net/blog/2012/05/04/hipchat-lwrp-for-chef</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since releasing a Campfire LWRP for Chef a few weeks ago, my team has evaluated
and subsequently transitioned to <a href="http://www.hipchat.com">Atlassian's HipChat service</a>.
Luckily I was able to reuse the framework I had already created for Campfire as the
basis for a HipChat LWRP.</p>

<p>The LWRP should work with any modern version of Chef. When you use <code>include_recipe</code>
to access the LWRP in your own recipes, the default recipe for this cookbook will install
the required <a href="http://rubygems.org/gems/hipchat">'hipchat' gem</a>.</p>

<h2>Attributes</h2>

<ul>
<li><code>room</code> - the name of the room you would like to speak into (requied).</li>
<li><code>token</code> - authentication token for your HipChat account (required).</li>
<li><code>nickname</code> - the nickname to be used when speaking the message (required).</li>
<li><code>message</code> - the message to speak. If a message is not specified, the name of the <code>hipchat_msg</code> resource is used.</li>
<li><code>notify</code> - toggles whether or not users in the room should be notified by this message (defaults to true).</li>
<li><code>color</code> - sets the color of the message in HipChat. Supported colors include: yellow, red, green, purple, or random (defaults to yellow).</li>
<li><code>failure_ok</code> - toggles whether or not to catch the exception if an error is encountered connecting to HipChat (defaults to true).</li>
</ul>


<h2>Usage example</h2>

<p>```ruby
include_recipe 'hipchat'</p>

<p>hipchat_msg 'bad news' do
  room 'The Pod Bay'
  token '0xdedbeef0xdedbeef0xdedbeef'
  nickname 'HAL9000'
  message "Sorry Dave, I'm afraid I can't do that: #{some_error}"
  color 'red'
end
```</p>

<h2>Availability</h2>

<p>You can find this cookbook <a href="http://www.github.com/cwjohnston/chef-hipchat">on github</a> or on the <a href="http://community.opscode.com/cookbooks/hipchat">Opscode community site</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
